

852 Centerwood Drive, Charleston, SC 29412

🛮 (631) 291-3866 | 💌 sam.chong.tay@gmail.com | 🏕 samtay.github.io | 🖫 samtay | 🛅 sam-tay

Summary _

Skillful problem solver with a background in pure mathematics and a passion for functional programming. 4+ years experience in web development, backend/infrastructure, and devops. Proven ability to quickly ramp up on new languages/technologies. Efficiency nerd who loves Linux, vim, and xmonad, and enjoys customizing the development environment.

Experience

Software Developer Aug 2017 - Present

WRINKL

Remote, U.S.

- Developed a websocket-driven chat application in Haskell.
- · Leveraged advanced type system features to achieve a high level of code safety.
- · Languages: Haskell, Nix.

Software Developer Apr 2017 - Aug 2017

EXPANDSHARE Charleston, SC

- Built core features and microservices for a Learning Manage System.
- Languages: Python, Javascript.

Applications Engineer May 2014 - Feb 2017

BLUE ACORN

- Charleston, SC • Developed reusable modules in an object oriented MVC eCommerce framework.
- Founded an educational Functional Programming group with weekly meetups.
- Led an agile team and mentored junior developers.
- Promoted from Apprentice to Senior within two years for exemplary work quality.
- Languages: PHP, Javascript, Bash, Haskell.

Research Assistant Summer 2011

ASTROPARTICULE ET COSMOLOGIE

Paris, France

· Conducted research and data analysis in correlation of temperature variation and phase noise for LOT (LISA On Table), an optical simulator for the LISA mission, under Dr. Hubert Halloin.

Skills

· Agile experience in both scrum and kanban, along with Jira, Pivotal, Workfront, and ZenHub.

Development

- Experience leading an agile team and mentoring junior developers.
- Experience with direct client interactions and discussing complex technological details with nontechnical stakeholders.

Languages

- Fluent in Haskell, Python, PHP, Javascript.
- Experience with Bash, C, C++.
- Frameworks: Snap, Reflex-Platform, Express, Django, Magento, Zend.

Software

- · Databases: Postgres, MySQL.
- Devops: Docker, Vagrant, Ansible, RabbitMQ.

Workflow

- · Proficient in Linux and MacOS.
- Enjoy maximizing productivity with development tools such as git, vim, tmux, xmonad, and zsh.

Education

Kenyon College Gambier, OH

B.S. IN MATHEMATICS AND SCIENTIFIC COMPUTING

Sep 2009 - May 2013

 Awarded Distinction on Senior Thesis · Achieved GPA of 3.91

Publications

Pattern Avoidance in Ternary Trees

Journal of Integer Sequences

Dec 2011

NATHAN GABRIEL, KATHERINE PESKE, LARA PUDWELL, AND SAMUEL TAY

http://arxiv.org/abs/1110.2225